

matteo@rizzi.xyz



### **Bachelor in Computer Science, Junior Research Scientist**

Born in 1998, 30 September, I work as a Junior Research Scientist in the <u>Security</u> and <u>Trust</u> unit at <u>Fondazione Bruno Kessler</u>. I joined the S&T unit to explore and improve TLS analysis and delve into identity management. I am working concurrently between FBK and the Istituto Poligrafico e Zecca dello Stato.

# **Experiences**

## Fondazione Bruno Kessler (Trento, Italy)

Junior Research Scientist ● Feb, 2021 - Present

Security analysis of the TLS deployments of <u>IPZS</u> projects, TLS Analysis in Android Apps and TLS tool enhancement within the Security & Trust research unit.

*Internship* ● *Feb, 2020 - May, 2020* 

Study and improvement of TLS analysis tools within the Security & Trust research unit.

# Futuro & Conoscenza S.r.l. (Trento & Rome, Italy)

Junior Research Scientist ● Jul, 2021 - Present

Collaboration between <u>Fondazione Bruno Kessler</u> and <u>IPZS</u> to promote the exchange of know-how and competences in the field of security technologies (material and digital) such as identification and anti-counterfeiting, as well as the creation of a center for the coordination and exploitation of research.

# **Papers**

### A Modular and Extensible Framework for Securing TLS

in 12th ACM Conference on Data and Application Security and Privacy, CODASPY ● Apr, 2022

Matteo Rizzi, Salvatore Manfredi, Giada Sciarretta, Silvio Ranise.

# **Projects**

### **breaking-telegram**

PoC script to break Telegram ● 2021

Simple PoC script that allows you to exploit telegram's "send with timer" feature by saving any media received with this functionality, automatically.

#### **TLSAssistant**

Version 1.3 and 2.0 to 2.3 • 2020 - Present

Fully-featured tool that combines state-of-the-art TLS analyzers with a report system that suggests appropriate mitigations and shows the full set of viable attacks.

#### **iHashDNA**

Perceptual hashing library in python ● 2020 - Present

Python library to easily check if two images are similar without machine learning by using Perceptual Hashing (phash and whash combined), with ban and unban image system.

# **Minor Works**

#### **Mallodroid**

Conversion in Python 3 and enhancements ● 2020 - 2021

#### telegram-deep-fakes-bot

Easy implementation and use of the first order model ● 2020

## Rappresentanti Bot

HelpDesk Telegram bot to support DISI Students in University of Trento ● 2019

# **Education**

## **University of Trento (Trento, Italy)**

Bachelor of Computer Science • Sept, 2017 - Mar, 2021

Thesis in TLS Analyzers for Android Apps - State-of-the-art Analysis and Integration in TLSAssistant.

# I.I.S. Primo Levi (Badia Polesine, Italy)

High School Diploma • Sept, 2012 - Sept, 2017

Final elaborate in psychoanalysis of James Joyce and the artificial intelligences.

# Certifications

## **CyberWiser - CyberRange And Capacity Building in CyberSecurity**

| Module    | Date         | Certificate     |
|-----------|--------------|-----------------|
| P-01-M-01 | May 19, 2021 | <u>Download</u> |
| P-01-M-02 | May 20, 2021 | <u>Download</u> |

| Module | Date         | Certificate     |
|--------|--------------|-----------------|
| P-02   | May 20, 2021 | <u>Download</u> |
| P-03   | May 20, 2021 | <u>Download</u> |
| P-04   | May 25, 2021 | <u>Download</u> |
| P-05   | June 4, 2021 | <u>Download</u> |
| P-06   | June 4, 2021 | <u>Download</u> |

#### **First Certificate**

Cambridge Assessment English - B2 ● Apr, 2017

#### **ECDL Base**

ECDL / ICDL Certification ● May, 2016

# **Programming Skills**

| Language                       | Knowledge Level            |
|--------------------------------|----------------------------|
| Python, Java, C (and C++), SQL | Advanced                   |
| Kotlin, PHP                    | Intermediate               |
| RUST                           | Basic (willing to improve) |
| JS, PolyML, R, ASM             | Basic                      |

# Soft Skills

# **University of Trento (Trento, Italy)**

Student Representative for DISI • Nov, 2018 - Nov, 2022

Department Of Information Engineering And Computer Science

